Kevin Wong

(917) 916 –0295 | Kevin.FNCW@gmail.com | Brooklyn, NY | linkedin.com/in/kfncw/ | github.com/Darktwine

SUMMARY

I am a junior full stack developer with in-depth experience building single-page applications with ReactJS, and also proficient in C++, JavaScript, Python, SQL. Enthusiastic about collaborating with others to apply problem solving skills to practical scenarios.

EDUCATION

Hunter College, City University of New York (CUNY)

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science | GPA: 3.94/4.00

New York, NY Expected May 2021

New York University

New York, NY 4/4.00 Sept 2014 – May 2018

Bachelor of Arts in Biology | GPA: 3.84/4.00

Relevant Coursework:

Data Structures and Algorithms, C++ Programming, Database Management, Discrete Mathematics, Computer Architecture, Computer Theory, Operating Systems, Cybersecurity, Blockchain, Web Development, Software Engineering

SKILLS

Languages: C++, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Solidity, SQL, MQL, R, Markdown, MIPS, Bash Technologies: Bootstrap, React, Express, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, GitHub, MacOS, Unix, Linux

Tools: Vim, Sublime, VSCode, Remix, Idle, MySQL Workbench, Compass, Heroku, Docker, Photoshop, Homebrew, npm

PROJECTS

Budgety

Sept 2020 – Dec 2020

• A user-friendly budget tracking web application built using Python, Flask, and SQL Alchemy. Users can set aside budgets and assign purchases to categories for a time period. Interface contains bar graphs and donut charts.

Token Escrow Contract Nov 2020 – Dec 2020

- A smart contract to be executed on the Ethereum blockchain, allowing users to buy and sell tokens using Ether
- Written in Solidity and tested/deployed on the Remix IDE, and supports standard ERC20 token functionality

Hunter College Cooperman Business Center Website

Dec 2019 - Jan 2020

- Redesigned Hunter College's Cooperman site as a deployed instance of WordPress under AWS
- Performed quality assurance, revising the site for broken links and ensured consistent document style

Omnifood Website Jan 2020 – March 2020

- Subscription-based food delivery service focused on organic, healthy, and diverse cuisines
- Built using HTML5 and CSS3, is a responsive and modern website optimized for mobile and tablet viewing

Ravenous Jan 2020

• Built a single-page web application allowing users to search for restaurant recommendations based on the type of food and location using ReactJS and Yelp API

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

CUNY Tech Prep

New York, NY

Fellow, Software Development

Jun 2020 – Present

- Selected for a technical training program, as one of 183 students out of 400+ applicants
- Learn in-demand technologies like React, Node + Express, and PostgreSQL as well as industry best practices for design, implementation, and deployment such as MVC, version control with Git/GitHub, agile & Scrum with Trello and Slack, test driven development, and CI/CD

Hunter College

New York, NY

Sept 2019 – December 2020

Teaching Assistant

- Instruct and tutor students in Python and C++
- Scan and grade quizzes/exams for 400+ students through Gradescope
- Conducted code review, providing guidance on programming assignments

SUPPORTING EXPERIENCE

NYU Langone Medical Center

New York, NY

Clinical Assistant

July 2018 - Jan 2019

- Involved in a research study involving IBD patients
- Collection and aliquot of blood and stool samples for analysis
- ELISA and DNA sequencing for families with multi-generational IBD
- Genotype analysis with PLINK to determine and at-risk genetic profiles

ASSOCIATIONS

Hunter Open Source Club, 2019 – Present